

CHRISTOPHE THIEBAUD

VIA BONAVIA 12, SAN LAZZARO DI SAVENA, 40068, ITALY. +49 176 81 20 33 24 CHRISTOPHE.T60@GMAIL.COM

I have been developing software since 1987, filling a number of different roles including Architect, People Manager, Project Manager, Lead Developer and Outside Advisor. What energizes me? A challenging position where I am able to build on decades of experience in the **creativity** + **technical expertise** + **people ecology** magical bundle to deliver truly beautiful software.

I am actively looking for a position in either **France**, or **Italy**, or ... both 😉











EXPERIENCE

ARCHITECT

SAP, WALLDORF, GERMANY

Hard skills: SAP Cloud Platform (CloudFoundry & Neo); Microservices; Git & Github; Jenkins & Travis; Docker; Continuous Deployment.

Soft skills: Internal Instructor ("Continuous Integration & DevOps" course); DevOps; Agile Processes & Scrum.

• Product Owner for a team of ten that was providing tools and service for non-abap / non-java internal development teams, i.e. C/C++ builds. As product Owner, my main duty was to define and prioritize the work items, à la scrum:

Christophe Thiebaud



- Develop new tools, chiefly around the maven ecosystem.
- Contribute to the management team on-going thinking process about the evolution of our technical environment. Evaluation of new 3rd party products, as well as migration of existing tools to new architectures.
- Consulting to external teams, especially when projects were so complex that our standard tooling was stretched to its limits; development and delivery of custom solutions/integrations for these projects.
- During all these years, I have been an early champion of cloud-based services, effectively and progressively moving functionalities of our legacy tools to REST apis and web interfaces.
- I ended up begin again Product Owner (as role, not title) for such a cloud based/rest api/web-ui product, code-named 'arcoiris', aimed to enable teams to take control of their software dependencies (internal and external).
- Finally, these last two years, I took a trainer part-time job for another department, training hundreds of developers on a course titled "Continuous Integration and DevOps".

November 2010 - December 2019

MANAGER

BUSINESS OBJECTS, PARIS, FRANCE

Hard skills: REST API design; System Performance Management.

Soft skills: Managing People; Managing Customer Escalation; Rolling out Engineering Processes and Tools, Worldwide.

February 2005 - November 2010

TEAM LEAD

UNIMATICA, BOLOGNA, ITALY

Hard skills: Linux & shell programming; Java; Javascript; HTTP & HTML & CSS; Web Servers (Tomcat & Websphere); Maven; XML; Digital Signature.

Soft skills: Web UI Design; Using and contributing to open source software.

January 2000 - February 2005

CONSULTANT

SELF-EMPLOYED, BOLOGNA, ITALY

Hard skills: Graph Algorithms; Game Programming; Macintosh Programming.

Soft skills: Selling myself; Selling one same software component to multiple customers.

September 1995 - January 2000

PROJECT MANAGER

CHIDOLOG MALINICH CEDMANNIV

Christophe Thiebaud



Soft skills: Juggling with external contractors; Juggling with internal politics.

July 1993 - July 1995

CODER

DATAID & COMELOG (SOFTWARE HOUSES), PARIS, FRANCE

Hard skills: Windows & OS/2 SDKs; C & C++; Relational Databases & SQL; System Integration.

Soft skills: Humility (being sold to customers as OOP guru); Team Lead.

July 1987 - July 1993

SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

ISI (HARDWARE RESELLER), PARIS, FRANCE

Hard skills: Everything (answering a wild variety of questions at the hot-line).

Soft skills: The Customer Is Always Right.

June 1986 - July 1987

EDUCATION

INSEAD, FONTAINEBLEAU, FRANCE

MBA

Finance

January 1992 - December 1992

CENTRE DE FORMATION BULL, MARNE LA VALLEE, FRANCE

PROGRAMMER ANALYST



ÉCOLE NORMALE DE MUSIQUE DE PARIS

DIPLÔME D'EXÉCUTION

Guitar

September 1978 - June 1982

LYCÉE POINCARÉ, NANCY, FRANCE

CLASSES PRÉPARATOIRES AUX GRANDES ECOLES

Mathématiques supérieures

September 1977 - June 1978

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS















PROCESSES

- ✓ Multi-cultural environment
- ✓ Agile Development & Scrum

LANGUAGES

- French, mother tongue
- English, fluent
- A Italian fluent



INTERESTS

In addition to being a geek, I am a fine guitar player, with a strong focus on JS Bach music (google for Thiebaud+Bach).



ॐ BIKE

~ 4000 kms per year, mostly commuting.





- « Why program by hand in 5 days what you can spend 5 years of your life automating?» Terence Parr
- « So convenient a thing it is to be a reasonable creature, since it enables one to find or make a reason for everything one has a mind to do. » Benjamin Franklin
- « Triple-double-quoted strings behave like double-quoted strings, with the addition that they are multiline, like the triple-single-quoted strings. » Groovy programming language documentation
- « Without the ball, you can't win. » Johan Cruyff

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

Y Business Objects Leadership Award





